# BECKY BARRACLOUGH

Social Media Specialist | 07824613674 | beckybarraclough@gmail.com

# ABOUT ME

Social media expert with over 10 years of experience planning and delivering a range of social marketing activities for large and small consumer brands, in house and agency. I've worked in the beauty, FMCG, fashion, travel, automotive, food and lifestyle sectors. View my portfolio here.

# STRENGTHS

- Deep understanding of social media channels and best practices
- · Strong attention to detail and efficiency
- · Excellent copywriter and creative storyteller
- Astute content planner
- Strategic and analytical
- · Inquisitive, keep up to date with culture & trend

## EXPERIENCE

#### May -July '22

#### Freelance Social Media Account Planner, eBay @ Byte DEPT

• Helping support the running of the eBay UK social channels. First port of call for the client and link between creatives and posting team

#### May 22

#### Freelance Social Media Manager, Beefeater Gin @ Pernod Ricard

- · Planning and posting for the Beefeater Gin Twitter account
- · Developed new Twitter strategy and TOV for the brand

#### Mar -Apr '22

#### Freelance Senior Social Media Strategist, LEGO @ Huge

- Worked as social media expert within strategy team to create new social media strategy for LEGO
- Collaborated with HUGE and LEGO global teams to produce work via multiple workshops and working sessions

#### Dec -Mar '22

#### Freelance Social Media Strategist, Marks and Spencer @ ODD London

- · Performed social media audit examining the performance of the M&S social channels
- · Created new social media strategy for the M&S Clothing & Home department
- Presented to client and collaborated with internal ODD teams

#### July '21 -Dec '21

# Freelance Social Media Strategist, NIVEA @ Publicis One Touch

- Created social & digital strategies for NIVEA product launches on channels such as Instagram, TikTok, Facebook, Pinterest, Spotify, Reddit and Twitch
- · Collaborated with wider teams, put together briefs for creatives and social listening agency
- Led on influencer projects; designed social concepts and create influencer playbooks

#### Nov '21 -Dec '21

## Freelance Community Manager, Volvo @ MediaBlaze

• Community management across FB, IG & Twitter for Volvo UK during periods of team leave

#### May -July '21

#### Freelance Social Media Manager, Just Eat @ Byte

- Worked closely with JET global team, managing UEFA EURO 2020 social campaign across 14 markets
- Led regular meetings with global and local marketing teams
- · Planned content calendar on Airtable, organising in line with asset deliveries and market matches
- · Worked closely with creatives to produce social assets
- Copywriting for social posts and organisation of local market translations

#### March -May '21

# Freelance Senior Social & Marketing Lead, Radley London

- · Managed the global social media, PR and marketing team with three direct reports
- Responsible for developing a new social media strategy and processes
- · Oversaw influencer marketing strategy and social activation of influencer campaigns
- · Led ideation and development of always-on social content
- · Led the monitoring and reporting process

August '20 -March '21

## Freelance Senior Social Media Manager, Hyundai @ Scholz and Friends (WPP)

- · Managed global social media accounts for Hyundai.Combined fan base of over 4M
- Social lead on the account, worked closely with multiple stakeholders across the agency including account management, creative, strategy and paid media teams
- Developed social first campaigns for client with regular client calls and presentations
- Role included creative ideation, concepting, content planning, strategy, channel and community management (using Falcon) and reporting.

June -Sept '20

# Freelance Social Media Strategist, Lillets, DEC, Gifflar, Google Cloud @ distillery

Worked on organic and paid social campaigns for clients, including an influencer campaign for Lillets, a YouTube campaign for the DEC and a social video campaign for Gifflar.

March '20 - Dec

## Freelance Social Media Manager, NIVEA, HBO & Warner @ Cheil

Covering periods of holiday and sick leave for the team. Tasks include social media and community management (using Sprinklr) content planning, creative management and reporting.

July '19-Feb '20

#### Digital Director, PURPLE

Head of digital for PURPLE, global agency for luxury brands in fashion, beauty & lifestyle

- · Worked closely with senior stakeholders, reporting into the company directors
- · Managed team of two. Directed the team's day to day agenda, workflow and deliverables
- · Led on responses to briefs; offered social strategy, management and paid social services
- · Introduced new planning and reporting process for the agency and clients

## Social Media & Advertising Manager UK & Ireland, M·A·C Cosmetics

June '15 -June '19 Social & advertising lead for the UK's biggest beauty brand & #1 global social beauty brand

- Launched the brand's first local market IG account, achieving 1M fans in 2½ years
- Led on MAC's first ever local 360 brand campaigns supporting foundation and lip Social Media Strategy:
- · Created regional social media strategy, social processes and guidelines
- · Campaign planning across organic channels in collaboration with wider teams
- Oversaw social media community management in line with brand TOV
- Utilised social tools to develop KPI focused monthly/campaign reports

#### Advertising:

- Managed media agency with regular status & strategy meetings, media briefings
- Led on campaign planning across all advertising channels; OOH, display, YT, social, cinema, VOD, partnerships (Refinery 29 & Vogue). Managed a £3M budget

#### Content Creation:

- Lead contact for external/internal creatives overseeing from concept to execution. Campaigns included: #WhatsYourThing Campaign: Winner of Glossy Award 'Best Use of Video by a Beauty Brand' & Vogue Award Runner up 'Most Memorable Ad Campaign' and for 'Services to Diversity' Vogue, OOH mural video #MeetYourMatte Lip Campaign: Partnership with Refinery 29
- Developed social strategy for LFW Sept 2015-Feb 2019. Provided creative direction to creatives
- Created live content via IG Stories & Snapchat at key events such as LFW or BAFTA
- · Recommended best practice for influencer content or attended influencer shoots

2014 - 15 Retail & Digital Marketing Executive UK, Triumph Lingerie

<sup>2010 - 14</sup> Marketing & PR Coordinator, White Stuff

2010 PR & Marketing Assistant, Rise Fashion

Fashion Assistant, Gok's Fashion Fix

# EDUCATION

London College of Fashion - Postgraduate Certificate in Fashion Marketing: 76% grade University of Leicester - BA History & Politics: 2:1 with honours, 1st for Dissertation William Farr, Lincoln - A-Levels: English A, Politics B, History C. AS level: Theatre B William Farr, Lincoln - GCSE's: 4 A\*s, 3 A's, 3B's